Presenter: OK, Eddie, first question for one hundred pounds.
A wolf can make a louder noise than a lion. True or false?
Eddie: A wolf can make a louder noise than a lion. Er, false, I’d say.
Presenter: Correct.
Wolves make a sound of approximately ninety decibels when they howl,
whereas a lion’s roar is about one hundred and fourteen decibels.
Now, for two hundred pounds, Stonehenge, the stone circle in the south-west of England,
is older than the Pyramids of Giza in Egypt. True or false?
Eddie: Er, I think it’s true.
Presenter: Correct.
It’s true. The construction of Stonehenge began about five thousand years ago,
but the construction of the pyramids actually began about four hundred and fifty years later.
Next, for four hundred pounds, the island of Cuba is bigger than the island of Iceland.
Eddie: I think it’s true. Cuba is much bigger than people think.
So yes, it’s true.
Presenter: Correct, though it’s not by much.
Cuba is about one hundred and nine thousand square metres and Iceland
is one hundred and three thousand square metres.
Next, for eight hundred pounds, Ireland is wetter than Brazil. True or false?
Eddie: Ireland is wetter than Brazil. Er, false.
I know it rains a lot in Ireland, but Brazil has rainforests, so I’m sure it rains more there.
Presenter: Correct.
The average rainfall in Brazil is one thousand seven hundred and sixty-one millimetres a year,
and in Ireland it’s only one thousand one hundred and eighteen.
Well, I say only, but it’s still quite a lot!
Well done, Eddie, that’s four correct answers so far.
Next, for one thousand six hundred pounds, a baby elephant is heavier than an adult panda.
True or false?
Eddie: Er, true. No, er, false. Er, I’m not sure.
Presenter: Do you want to phone a friend?
Eddie: No, I think it’s true.
I know baby pandas are tiny, and maybe even full-grown ones aren’t as heavy as we might think.
I’m saying it’s true.
Presenter: Correct.
A newborn baby elephant can weigh as much as one hundred and twenty kilograms,
but an adult panda never weighs more than one hundred and thirteen kilograms.
OK, for three thousand two hundred pounds, life in New York is more expensive than life in Paris.
Eddie: Er, true. I’m pretty sure New York is more expensive.
Presenter: Correct.
New York is usually in the top five in the list of expensive cities to live in, along with Zurich and Singapore.
Paris is still expensive of course, but it’s a lot cheaper than New York at the moment.
OK, Eddie, now question seven, for six thousand four hundred pounds –
the mountain K-two is more difficult to climb than Mount Kilimanjaro. True or false?
Eddie: Er, I think that’s true. I know K-two is incredibly dangerous.
Presenter: Well done, Eddie.
Twenty-five per cent of the people who climb K-two die, usually on the way down,
but fewer than 1% of the people who climb Kilimanjaro die.
And finally, the last question.
Be very careful, Eddie. If you get it right, you win twelve thousand eight hundred pounds,
but if you get it wrong, you get nothing.
Are you ready?
Eddie: Yes, ready.
Presenter: OK, for twelve thousand eight hundred pounds,
white chocolate is better for you than milk chocolate.
Eddie: Er…er…
Presenter: I need your answer, Eddie.
Eddie: I think it’s true, but I’m not sure. I want to phone a friend.
Presenter: Right, Eddie.
So, who do you want to call?
Eddie: Er, my dad, Brian.
Presenter: OK, then. Hello, is that Brian?
Mia: No, it’s Mia.
Presenter: Er, I’m phoning from Quiz Night. Is Brian there?
Mia: Dad’s not here. I’m Eddie’s sister. I can help.
Presenter: OK, Mia, Eddie needs some help.
You have thirty seconds, Eddie. Here she is.
Eddie: OK…Hi, Mia, listen…
Mia: Hi, Eddie.
Eddie: It’s the last question in the quiz.
‘White chocolate is better for you than milk chocolate’. I think it’s true.
Mia: Er, OK, I’m sure there’s more sugar in white chocolate.
I think it’s false.
Eddie: Um, I don’t think so. I think white chocolate is healthier.
Mia: I’m right on this one, Eddie.
Eddie: OK, um, really difficult, I can’t decide.
Presenter: Time’s up, I’m afraid. OK, Eddie. So, true or false?
Eddie: Er, oh, I don’t know, I don’t think she’s right. I’m going to say true.
Presenter: Final answer?
Eddie: Final answer. True.
Presenter: I’m sorry, Eddie, it’s false.
In one hundred grams of white chocolate, there is fifty-nine grams of sugar,
in milk chocolate it’s fifty-two grams.
Eddie, you had six thousand four hundred pounds, but now you go home with…nothing.